Rachel Wildberger

CREATIVE DIRECTOR | GRAPHIC DESIGNER | JUNIOR DEVELOPER

Phone 213.921.0610

Email rachel@ohyeahcreative.com

Portfolio ohyeahcreative.com

GitHub github.com/RachelWildberger

Work Experience

Vallure Agency | Senior Graphic Designer | 2021 to present

Created standards for design excellence within the design team. Core expertise rooted in UI UX Design creating websites, and digitally connected marketing and products. Created user centered experiences, brand identity systems, and digital content, from concept to launch.

- Expertise of UI UX, with increasing integrity of design (storyboarding, wireframing, visual mockups, prototypes, Wordpress, Elementor, Shopify, Squarespace).
- Developed powerful campaigns that stretch across site, email, social and paid channels.
- Lead creative on key initiatives across the Vallure Agency network of brands—helped to establish a cross-brand backdrop and elevate our creative output.

Oh Yeah Creative | Freelance, Art Direction & Design | 2019 to present

Directly work with business and brands to deliver brilliant creative ideas for branding, digital design, art direction, collateral, and web design and development. Identify business needs and offer a diverse selection of creative solutions across various budgets and platforms.

- Composed and built strong visual stories that blend strategy, design, and brand.
- Created visual design standards for businesses and ensured consistency across all channels with a focus on digital and social.
- Provided clear creative guidance to clients and external partners at all levels.

Sincerely Jules | Art Direction & Graphic Design | 2016 to 2018

Maintained creative brand wide supporting the direction and vision of the creative director. Designed and developed high-quality work and collaborated with marketing, PR, post-production, and web developers to produce quality, on-brand marketing campaigns.

- Created an email marketing strategy with coordinated digital advertising on multiple channels, achieving desired goals of gaining subscribers and increasing sales.
- Innovated and contributed design thinking and creative problem solving throughout the brand while following brand standards ensuring consistency and quality.

Issue, Inc. | Graphic Designer | 2013 to 2015

Collaborative designer for a full-service creative agency, providing graphic design, web design, branding, online marketing, photography editing, and shoot production; with the goal of heightening brand identities across all mediums.

- Produced advertisement materials, mood-boards, logos, typography, color schemes and landing pages to support campaigns.
- Showed ability to work under tight deadlines, delivering work that is accurate and innovative alongside consistent attention to detail.

Summary

Junior Full-Stack Web Developer and accomplished Graphic Designer with 10+ years of agency and design experience. Specializing in UX UI, front-end web projects, brand-identity, marketing campaigns, e-commerce and digital content production.

Inspired to create playful and smart experiences, using problem solving through sleek, sophisticated design and development. With both creative and technical ability, ready for any challenging project from ideation to creation.

Education

Full Stack Web Developement Certificate

The University of Arizona
Continuing and Professional Education

Bachelor of Fine Arts in Graphic Design

School of Art and Design The University of Illinois at Chicago

Technical Skills

Adobe Creative Suite, Figma, Squarespace, Shopify, Wordpress, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, JQuery, Express, MongoDB, MySQL

Web Development Projects

Get a Job: Job Board Application | Interactive Full Stack Project

Built a job board application site, where users can publish jobs, create an account, upload a resume and search for jobs. Front end built with Bulma and focused on a modern, simplified UI UX design.

Technologies Used | Node.js, Express.js, Handlebars.js, MySQL and Sequelize ORM, Bulma CSS Framework

Dinner and Drinks Application | Front End Project

Created an easy to use food and drink app that accepts and responds to user input with dinner and drink recipes. by integrating data received from multiple server-side API requests. This application also interacts with data received from multiple server-side API Requests.

Technologies Used | Bulma CSS Framework, GitHub Pages